herothemes.com 2019-06-29

# HeroThemes Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Heroic Media Ltd’s (“HeroThemes”) privacy policy is set out below.

HeroThemes respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

This privacy policy is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy policy.

## Important Information And Who We Are

 **Purpose of this privacy policy**

This privacy policy aims to give you information on how HeroThemes collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our newsletter or purchase a subscription from us.

This website and the Services are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy policy together with any other privacy policy or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

 **Controller**

HeroThemes is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as HeroThemes, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy).

 **Contact details**

Full name of legal entity: Heroic Media Ltd

You can contact us from our[ Contact Form](https://herothemes.com/contact/)

Postal address: The Glades, Festival Way, Stoke-On-Trent, England, ST1 5SQ

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the [Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO)](https://ico.org.uk/), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

Changes to the privacy policy and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated on 15 May 2018.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

 **Third-party links**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

## The Data We Collect About You

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * Identity Data includes username or similar identifier.
  * Contact Data includes billing address, email address.
  * Financial Data includes payment card details.
  * Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of subscriptions you have purchased from us.
  * Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * Profile Data includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  * Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific theme or plug-in feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

 **Financial Payment Data**

We do not process any payment card details or details of payments to or from you. Stripe and PayPal are the payment processors which collect these details in order to process subscription payments (and any cancellation refunds). The collection and processing of your payment card details in accordance with our payment processor’s privacy policy, which is contained in the [Stripe privacy policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy) and the [PayPal privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

## How Your Personal Data Is Collected

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by using the HeroThemes website, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * apply for our subscriptions;
  * create an account on our website;
  * subscribe to our themes, plug-ins and support and maintenance services;
  * request marketing to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us some feedback.

Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns.

We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. Please see our [cookie policy](https://herothemes.com/cookie-policy/) for further details.

## How We Use Your Personal Data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

Where we need for the performance of a contract with you: that is, to provide our subscription services to you.

Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Where there is a Lawful Basis to do so.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by using the ‘unsubscribe’ link in our emails, or by contacting us.

 **Purposes for which we will use your personal data**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity| Type of data| Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer| 

  * Identity
  * Contact

| 

  * Performance of a contract with you

To process and deliver your order including:

  * Manage payments, fees and charges through Stripe and PayPal

| 

  * Identity
  * Contact
  * Financial
  * Transaction

| 

  * Performance of a contract with you

To manage our subscription and relationship with you which will include:

  * Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
  * Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| 

  * Identity
  * Contact
  * Profile

| 

  * Performance of a contract with you
  * Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)

To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, fraud prevention, support, reporting and hosting of data)| 

  * Identity
  * Contact
  * Technical

| 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)
  * Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences| 

  * Technical

| 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)

To make suggestions and recommendations to you about other themes and plugins that may be of interest to you| 

  * Identity
  * Contact
  * Technical

| 

  * Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)

 **Marketing**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

 **Promotional offers from us**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).  
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased subscriptions from us and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

 **Third-party marketing**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside HeroThemes for marketing purposes.

 **Opting out**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time.

 **Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://herothemes.com/cookie-policy/).

 **Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

## Disclosures Of Your Personal Data

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.

The following external service providers:

  * Stripe, who provide us with payment processing services;
  * Carthook, who provide us with a service which captures your email address during the purchase process to enable us to contact you in the event of an abandoned purchase process;
  * Mailchimp, who provide us with email campaign services;
  * OptinMonster, who help us with user engagement on our website;
  * Kinsta, who provide hosting services;

Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services;

HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities;

Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

## International Transfers

Some of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: [Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).

Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: [Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).

Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

## Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## Data Retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: please contact us if you would like us to do so.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## Your Legal Rights

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include the right to request from us access to and rectification or erasure of personal data; restriction of processing concerning you; to object to processing as well as the right to data portability. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

 **No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

 **What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

 **Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## Glossary

 **Lawful Basis**

Legitimate Interest – means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

Performance of Contract – means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation – means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
